School of the Museum of Fine Arts Records UA133
Tufts Archival Research Center
- Audiovisual materials, 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011; 14.4 Linear Feet
  - Faculty Lecture Series, 2004-11-03; UA133.011.085.00131 (Box 85)
  - Visiting Artist Lecture, 2004-10-14; UA133.011.085.00132 (Box 85)
  - Visiting Artist Lecture, 2004-09-27; UA133.011.085.00133 (Box 85)
  - Four Sculptors Lecture Series, 2004-10-05; UA133.011.085.00134 (Box 85)
  - Eight Sculptors Lecture Series, 2005-02-15; UA133.011.085.00135 (Box 85)
  - Visiting Artist Lecture, 2004-09-23; UA133.011.085.00136 (Box 85)
  - Ken Feingold, 2004-09-23; UA133.011.085.00137 (Box 85)
  - Visiting Artist Lecture, 2004-09-22; UA133.011.085.00138 (Box 85)
  - Tripp Evans - Wheaton lecture, 2004-09-22; UA133.011.085.00139 (Box 85)
  - Beckwith Lecture, 2004-10-04; UA133.011.085.00140 (Box 85)
  - Beckwith Lecture, 2004-10-04; UA133.011.085.00141 (Box 85)
  - Unmasking Shadow, 2004-07-10; UA133.011.085.00142 (Box 85)
  - Four Painters Lecture Series, 2004-09-27; UA133.011.085.00143 (Box 85)
  - Four Painters Lecture Series, 2004-08-03; UA133.011.085.00144 (Box 85)
  - Four Sculptors Lecture Series, 2004-10-19; UA133.011.085.00145 (Box 85)
  - Triple Candie, 2004; UA133.011.085.00146 (Box 85)
    Candie, Triple
  - Faculty Lecture Series, 2004-09-29; UA133.011.085.00147 (Box 85)
  - Four Painters Lecture Series, 2005-10-04; UA133.011.085.00148 (Box 85)
  - Four Painters Lecture Series, 2005-10-04; UA133.011.085.00149 (Box 85)
  - Bruce McClure, 2005-02-15; UA133.011.085.00150 (Box 85)
    McClure, Bruce
  - Faculty Lecture Series, 2005-09-14; UA133.011.085.00151 (Box 85)
  - Jessica Stockholder, 2005-10-06; UA133.011.085.00152 (Box 85)
    Stockholder, Jessica
  - Jessica Stockholder, 2005-10-06; UA133.011.085.00153 (Box 85)
  - Eight Sculptors Lecture, 2005-02-22; UA133.011.085.00154 (Box 85)
  - Four Sculptors Lecture Series, 2005-09-14; UA133.011.085.00155 (Box 85)
  - Linda Norden, 2005-09-27; UA133.011.085.00156 (Box 85)
  - Beckwith Lecture: W. J. T. Mitchell, 2005-09-19; UA133.011.085.00157 (Box 85)
  - Meet the Jury, 2005; UA133.011.085.00158 (Box 85)
    Stover, William; Yezerski, Howard; Goldberg, Vicki; Miller, Cecily
  - Four Sculptors Lecture Series, 2004-09-21; UA133.011.085.00159 (Box 85)
  - Four Sculptors Lecture Series, 2004-09-21; UA133.011.085.00160 (Box 85)
  - Four Sculptors Lecture Series, 2004-03-16; UA133.011.085.00161 (Box 85)
  - The Body of the Text, 2004-03-03; UA133.011.085.00162 (Box 85)
  - Four Painters Lecture Series, 2004-11-01; UA133.011.085.00163 (Box 85)
  - Four Sculptors Lecture Series, 2008-03-11; UA133.011.085.00164 (Box 85)
  - Dave Hickey, 2000-01-01; UA133.011.085.00165 (Box 85)
  - Four Sculptors Lecture Series, 2008-03-11; UA133.011.085.00166 (Box 85)
  - Valerie Hegarty, 2008-10-28; UA133.011.085.00167 (Box 85)
  - Visiting Artist Lecture, 2004-10-07; UA133.011.085.00168 (Box 85)
  - Visiting Artist Lecture, 2004-10-13; UA133.011.085.00169 (Box 85)
  - Visiting Artist Lecture, 2004-10-13; UA133.011.085.00170 (Box 85)
  - Il Spaghetti Occidentali (Spaghetti Western), 2002; UA133.011.086.00001 (Box 86)
    Warmouth, Jeff
  - Untitled, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.086.00002 (Box 86)
  - Chronicle: Against Type, 2005-02-01; UA133.011.086.00003 (Box 86)
  - SMFA Open Studios - WBZ, 2002-03-07; UA133.011.086.00004 (Box 86)
  - Isa Dean, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.086.00005 (Box 86)
    Dean, Isa
  - Chisels and Chainsaws - Fox News spot, 2003-02-21; UA133.011.086.00006 (Box 86)
  - Fifty Years of Painting w/ Dr. Tritobia Benjamin, 2006-09-27; UA133.011.086.00007 (Box 86)
  - Synchrony in Estrus, 2002; UA133.011.086.00008 (Box 86)
    Edward, Thomas; Denio, Amy
  - SMFA promotional video duplicate, circa 1990 -- 1999; UA133.011.086.00009 (Box 86)
  - Pain; The Digital Dream; The Studio; The Tree of My Grand Mother's House, 2001; UA133.011.086.00010 (Box 86)
    El Noshokaty, Shady
  - Chronicle: John Corso and Sophia Ainslie, 2001-06-25; UA133.011.086.00011 (Box 86)
    Corso, John; Ainslie, Sophia
  - PBS: American Talent; Chronicle: Against Type; TLC: What Not to Wear, 2004-09-22, 2005-02-01, 2005-04-16; UA133.011.086.00012 (Box 86)
  - PBS: American Talent; Chronicle: Against Type; TLC: What Not to Wear, 2004-09-22, 2005-02-01, 2005-04-16; UA133.011.086.00013 (Box 86)
  - PBS: American Talent; TLC: What Not to Wear, 2004-09-22, 2005-04-16; UA133.011.086.00014 (Box 86)
  - Antoniadis and Stone lecture, 2013-04-09; UA133.011.086.00015 (Box 86)
  - 2013 Hale Lecturer: Matthew Day Jackson - round table discussion, 2013-04-04; UA133.011.086.00016 (Box 86)
  - Annie Hann and Daniel Mihalyo (Lead Pencil Studio) lecture, 2013-04-02; UA133.011.086.00017 (Box 86)
    Hann, Annie; Mihalo, Dawel
  - Thomas Eggerer lecture, 2013-03-28; UA133.011.086.00018 (Box 86)
  - Bill Arning lecture, 2013-03-26; UA133.011.086.00019 (Box 86)
  - Latoya Ruby Frazier lecture, 2013-03-14; UA133.011.086.00020 (Box 86)
  - Julia Jacquette lecture, 2013-03-07; UA133.011.086.00021 (Box 86)
  - Andrea Geyer lecture, 2013-02-28; UA133.011.086.00022 (Box 86)
  - Nayland Blake lecture, 2013-02-26; UA133.011.086.00023 (Box 86)
  - Manjari Sharma lecture, 2014-04-01; UA133.011.086.00024 (Box 86)
  - Philip Taaffe lecture, 2014-04-03; UA133.011.086.00025 (Box 86)
  - Scott McCarney and Keith Smith lecture, 2014-04-10; UA133.011.086.00026 (Box 86)
  - Jane Marshing lecture, 2014-04-15; UA133.011.086.00027 (Box 86)
    Marshing, Jane
  - Zoe Beloff lecture, 2014-04-16; UA133.011.086.00028 (Box 86)
  - William Villalongo lecture, 2014-04-17; UA133.011.086.00029 (Box 86)
  - Laida Lertxundi lecture (2 of 2), 2014-03-26; UA133.011.086.00030 (Box 86)
  - Laida Lertxundi lecture (1 of 2), 2014-03-26; UA133.011.086.00031 (Box 86)
  - Nina Katchadourian lecture, 2014-03-13; UA133.011.086.00032 (Box 86)
  - Hilton Als Hale Visiting Artist lecture, 2014-03-07; UA133.011.086.00033 (Box 86)
  - Carrie Moyer lecture, 2014-03-06; UA133.011.086.00034 (Box 86)
  - Mary Reid Kelley and Patrick Kelley lecture, 2014-03-05; UA133.011.086.00035 (Box 86)
    Kelley, Mary Reid; Kelley, Patrick
  - Dawit Petros lecture, 2014-02-27; UA133.011.086.00036 (Box 86)
  - Lisi Raskin lecture, 2014-02-25; UA133.011.086.00037 (Box 86)
    Raskin, Lisi
  - Daniel Bozhkov lecture, 2014-02-11; UA133.011.086.00038 (Box 86)
  - Sage Sohier lecture, 2014-02-06; UA133.011.086.00039 (Box 86)
  - Gideon Bok lecture, 2014-01-30; UA133.011.086.00040 (Box 86)
  - Mohamed Abla lecture, 2012-02-21; UA133.011.086.00041 (Box 86)
  - Janie Geiser lecture (1 of 2), 2012-03-06; UA133.011.086.00042 (Box 86)
  - Janie Geiser lecture (2 of 2), 2012-03-06; UA133.011.086.00043 (Box 86)
  - John Divola lecture, 2012-03-08; UA133.011.086.00044 (Box 86)
  - Alison Elizabeth Taylor lecture, 2012-03-15; UA133.011.086.00045 (Box 86)
  - Eileen Quinlan lecture, 2012-03-29; UA133.011.086.00046 (Box 86)
  - David Humphrey, 2012-04-12; UA133.011.086.00047 (Box 86)
  - Emma Bowkett lecture, 2012-04-19; UA133.011.086.00048 (Box 86)
  - Henry Horenstein, 2013-11-21; UA133.011.086.00049 (Box 86)
  - Eve Laramee lecture, 2013-11-19; UA133.011.086.00050 (Box 86)
  - Donald Moffett lecture, 2013-11-14; UA133.011.086.00051 (Box 86)
  - Wendy Jacob, 2013-11-05; UA133.011.086.00052 (Box 86)
  - Jackie Saccoccio lecture, 2013-10-31; UA133.011.086.00053 (Box 86)
  - Amy Stein lecture, 2013-10-24; UA133.011.086.00054 (Box 86)
  - Ben Rubin lecture, 2013-10-22; UA133.011.086.00055 (Box 86)
    Rubin, Ben
  - Steve Locke lecture, 2013-10-17; UA133.011.086.00056 (Box 86)
  - Elijah Gowin lecture, 2013-10-10; UA133.011.086.00057 (Box 86)
  - Barnaby Furnas lecture, 2013-10-03; UA133.011.086.00058 (Box 86)
  - Heather Dewey - Hagborg lecture, 2013-10-01; UA133.011.086.00059 (Box 86)
    Dewey-Hagborg, Heather
  - Sarah Malakoff lecture, 2013-09-26; UA133.011.086.00060 (Box 86)
  - Jorge Antonio Fernández - Torres, 2013-09-10; UA133.011.086.00061 (Box 86)
  - Henry Horenstein lecture, 2013-07-14; UA133.011.086.00062 (Box 86)
  - Cheyney Thompson, 2012-02-16; UA133.011.086.00063 (Box 86)
  - Sue Vanderheck lecture, 2012-02-16; UA133.011.086.00064 (Box 86)
  - Fred Tomaselli lecture, 2013-04-11; UA133.011.086.00065 (Box 86)
  - Gilles Roussel (Boulet) lecture, 2013-04-10; UA133.011.086.00066 (Box 86)
  - Brittany Gravely - Traveling Scholars application 2008, UA133.011.086.00067 (Box 86)
    Gravely, Brittany
  - Tribute to Bill Bagnall, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.086.00068 (Box 86)
  - Tribute to Bill Bagnall loop tape, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.086.00069 (Box 86)
  - Dana Frankfort, 2010-10-12; UA133.011.086.00070 (Box 86)
  - Chris Verene, 2010-11-18; UA133.011.086.00071 (Box 86)
  - Diana Punter, 2010-11-23; UA133.011.086.00072 (Box 86)
  - Diana Punter, 2010-11-23; UA133.011.086.00073 (Box 86)
  - Mags Harries, 2010-09-20; UA133.011.086.00074 (Box 86)
  - Jennifer Dalton, 2010-09-21; UA133.011.086.00075 (Box 86)
  - Wendy White, 2009-03-24; UA133.011.086.00076 (Box 86)
  - Steve Dibenedetto lecture, 2013-02-07; UA133.011.086.00077 (Box 86)
  - Florencio Gelabert, 2010-10-05; UA133.011.086.00078 (Box 86)
  - Florencio Gelabert copy, 2010-10-05; UA133.011.086.00079 (Box 86)
  - Michael Rees, 2010-11-29; UA133.011.086.00080 (Box 86)
  - Annie Auchere Aguettaz, 2010-09-14; UA133.011.086.00081 (Box 86)
    Aguettaz, Annie Auchere
  - Poetics of Memory, 2010-09-15; UA133.011.086.00082 (Box 86)
  - Beckwith Lecture, 2010-09-27; UA133.011.086.00083 (Box 86)
    Mergel, Jen
  - Charline Von Heyl, 2010-09-28; UA133.011.086.00084 (Box 86)
    Von Heyl, Charline
  - David Davison, 2010-09-29; UA133.011.086.00085 (Box 86)
  - The Ohus 09/10, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.086.00086 (Box 86)
    Sledgianowski, Joseph
  - Combat Paper, 2009-09-17; UA133.011.086.00087 (Box 86)
    Combat Paper
  - Four Photographers Lecture Series - Disc 1 of 2, 2009-09-24; UA133.011.086.00088 (Box 86)
  - Four Photographers Lecture Series - Disc 2 of 2, 2009-09-24; UA133.011.086.00089 (Box 86)
  - Go Out on a Limb, Beat Around the Bush, 2009; UA133.011.086.00090 (Box 86)
    Citowsky, Lana
  - Sanford Biggers, 2009-10-13; UA133.011.086.00091 (Box 86)
  - Beckwith Lecture, 2009-09-23; UA133.011.086.00092 (Box 86)
    Berman, Kim
  - Karl Baden, 2009-10-22; UA133.011.086.00093 (Box 86)
  - Karl Baden, 2009-10-22; UA133.011.086.00094 (Box 86)
  - Hamra Abbas, 2009-10-02; UA133.011.086.00095 (Box 86)
  - Hamra Abbas, 2009-10-02; UA133.011.086.00096 (Box 86)
  - Phoebe Washburn, 2009-09-23; UA133.011.086.00097 (Box 86)
  - Temporary Services, 2011-04-19; UA133.011.086.00098 (Box 86)
  - Erin Shirreff, 2011-04-14; UA133.011.086.00099 (Box 86)
  - Tauba Auerbach, 2011-04-12; UA133.011.086.00100 (Box 86)
  - Alix Pearlstein, 2011-04-05; UA133.011.086.00101 (Box 86)
  - Dasha Shishkin, 2011-03-29; UA133.011.086.00102 (Box 86)
  - Patti Smith, 2011-03-16; UA133.011.086.00103 (Box 86)
  - Nicole Cherubini, 2011-03-15; UA133.011.086.00104 (Box 86)
  - 5th Year Artist Talks, 2011-03-13; UA133.011.086.00105 (Box 86)
  - Bradley McCallum, 2011-03-10; UA133.011.086.00106 (Box 86)
  - Daniel Dove, 2011-03-01; UA133.011.086.00107 (Box 86)
  - Emily Roysdon, 2011-02-17; UA133.011.086.00108 (Box 86)
  - Matt Saunders, 2011-02-15; UA133.011.086.00109 (Box 86)
  - Student Artist Talks, 2011-02-14; UA133.011.086.00110 (Box 86)
  - Kristin Baker - DVD 2 of 2, 2011-02-07; UA133.011.086.00111 (Box 86)
  - Kristin Baker - DVD 1 of 2, 2011-02-07; UA133.011.086.00112 (Box 86)
  - Kristin Baker - DVD 2 of 2, 2011-02-07; UA133.011.086.00113 (Box 86)
  - Kristin Baker - DVD 1 of 2, 2011-02-07; UA133.011.086.00114 (Box 86)
  - Franklin Evans, 2011-10-27; UA133.011.086.00115 (Box 86)
  - Simulations, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.086.00116 (Box 86)
    Stempel, Angela
  - Chair Danger, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.086.00117 (Box 86)
    Alpert, Bruce
  - Loss Tape; Babydish, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.086.00118 (Box 86)
  - Bruce Alpert; Bill Flynn; Donald Sibley, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.086.00119 (Box 86)
    Alpert, Bruce; Flynn, Bill; Sibley, Donald
  - Senior Projects - Anderson Auditorium and Grossman Gallery, 2010; UA133.011.086.00120 (Box 86)
  - Senior Projects - Anderson Auditorium and Atrium, 2010; UA133.011.086.00121 (Box 86)
  - Senior Projects, 2016; UA133.011.086.00122 (Box 86)
  - Volunteer training - Inside Out, 2009; UA133.011.086.00123 (Box 86)
  - Untitled, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.086.00124 (Box 86)
  - Untitled, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.086.00125 (Box 86)
  - Untitled, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.086.00126 (Box 86)
  - Untitled, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.086.00127 (Box 86)
  - Jonathan Moller - Museum School news, 2002-06-04; UA133.011.086.00128 (Box 86)
    Moller, Jonathan
  - Nan Freeman interview, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.086.00129 (Box 86)
  - Untitled, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.086.00130 (Box 86)
  - TIlting at Space - (card for Tina Barney attached), 1994-01-01; UA133.011.087.00001 (Box 87)
    Groover, Jan
  - German Art - It's Heritage and the New Territory, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.087.00002 (Box 87)
  - Graduate 1995 BFA, Whitney 2008, 1992-01-01; UA133.011.087.00003 (Box 87)
    Fast, Omer
  - 1-Cold Stories, 2-Defenses, 3-Breaking and Entering - 3 Part Video Novel, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.087.00004 (Box 87)
    Kernan, Margot Starr
  - Miroslav Antic, 2000-01-01; UA133.011.087.00005 (Box 87)
    Antic, Miroslav
  - Roberta Smith, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.087.00006 (Box 87)
    Smith, Roberta
  - John Schulz, 2000-01-01; UA133.011.087.00007 (Box 87)
    Schulz, John
  - Beckwith Lecture - Unframing Experience, 2006-09-16; UA133.011.087.00008 (Box 87)
  - Combat Paper, 2009-09-17; UA133.011.087.00009 (Box 87)
  - Barry Gaither, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.087.00010 (Box 87)
  - Eight Sculptors Lecture Series, 2007-09-18; UA133.011.087.00011 (Box 87)
  - Dave Hickey, 2000-01-01; UA133.011.087.00012 (Box 87)
  - Dream Keepers - N. Hampshire Public Broadcasting Appearance, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.087.00013 (Box 87)
    Dream Keepers
  - Faculty Lecture Series, 2007-10-10; UA133.011.087.00014 (Box 87)
  - Dave Hickey, 2000-01-01; UA133.011.087.00015 (Box 87)
  - Faculty Lecture Series, 2000-01-01; UA133.011.087.00016 (Box 87)
  - Eight Photographers Lecture Series, 2007-09-20; UA133.011.087.00017 (Box 87)
  - Wheaton College, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.087.00018 (Box 87)
  - Beckwith Lecture, 2009-09-23; UA133.011.087.00019 (Box 87)
  - Yun-Fei Ji, 2008-09-10; UA133.011.087.00020 (Box 87)
    Ji, Yun-Fei
  - Four Painters Lecture Series, 2007-10-16; UA133.011.087.00021 (Box 87)
  - AIDS Day (various years), 1999-01-01; UA133.011.087.00022 (Box 87)
  - Bly Workshop, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.087.00023 (Box 87)
  - Sanity is Madness - Interrelated Arts Foundation Boston, 1989; UA133.011.087.00024 (Box 87)
    Pierson, Mark
  - Julie Graham, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.087.00025 (Box 87)
    Graham, Julie
  - Gallery Talk, 2001-11-01; UA133.011.087.00026 (Box 87)
  - Eight Painters Lecture, 2007-10-02; UA133.011.087.00027 (Box 87)
  - Doug and Mike Starn, 2000-01-01; UA133.011.087.00028 (Box 87)
  - Beckwith Lecture, 2007-10-03; UA133.011.087.00029 (Box 87)
  - Eight Sculptors Lecture Series, 2007-10-09; UA133.011.087.00030 (Box 87)
  - Chiapas Photography Project, 2007-10-01; UA133.011.087.00031 (Box 87)
    Duarte, Carlota
  - Harvard Curator, 2007-10-02; UA133.011.087.00032 (Box 87)
  - Head Bodies, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.087.00033 (Box 87)
    Bach, Claus
  - Workshop, 1998-01-01; UA133.011.087.00034 (Box 87)
  - Nepalese Sacred Dance, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.087.00035 (Box 87)
    Rajendra and his Troupe
  - Triple Candie, 2004; UA133.011.087.00036 (Box 87)
  - Meet the Jurors, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.087.00037 (Box 87)
  - Fade to Black - Interrelated Arts Foundation, 1992-01-01; UA133.011.087.00038 (Box 87)
    Cokes, Tony
  - Light from Other Skies, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.087.00039 (Box 87)
    Beckwith, Lolo
  - Nepalese Sacred Dance, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.087.00040 (Box 87)
  - Visiting Artist lecture: group material, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.087.00041 (Box 87)
  - Rebecca Barron, circa 1980 -- 2016; UA133.011.087.00042 (Box 87)
    Barron, Rebecca
  - Doug and Mike Starn, 2000-01-01; UA133.011.087.00043 (Box 87)
- Photographs, circa 1970 -- 2013; UA133.012; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series consists of photographs, slides, and negatives of artwork, people, events, and the SMFA campus dating from the 1970s to the early 2000s. Most of the people pictured are students, faculty, and staff of the SMFA. Artworks are unlabeled and unidentified.
  - Art, students, and faculty photographs, circa 1970 -- 2005; UA133.012.012 (Box 12)
  - Karsh Award portfolio of Nickolas van de Kamp, 2013; UA133.012.068 (Box Small Map Case 2 Drawer 3)
- Publications, 1979 -- 2018; UA133.013; 1.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains publications from 1979 to 2018, including course brochures, exhibit brochures, facebooks, newsletters, student handbooks, and an alumni directory. There are mostly complete runs of Museum School News from 1979 to 2002 and its successor artMatters from 2003 to 2009. This series also includes a few non-SMFA publications pertaining to art.
  - Publications, 1979 -- 2013; UA133.013.006 (Box 6)
  - Non-School of the Museum of Fine Arts publications, 1999 -- 2012; UA133.013.012 (Box 12)
  - Publications, Spring, 2018; UA133.013.443.00001; .1 Linear Feet 1 folder (Box 443)
  - Publications, Fall, 2018; UA133.013.443.00002; .1 Linear Feet 1 Folder (Box 443)
- 2019 accessions, 1875 -- 2016; UA133.014; Museum of Fine Arts, Boston. School; 129.88 Linear Feet 90 record cartons; 54 bound items; 6 document boxes; 5 oversize boxes.
  University records are closed for 20 years from the date of creation. Records older than 20 years that do not pertain to student education, staff and faculty employment, and Board of Trustees records are open for research. This series may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
  Transferred from the MFA archives, 2019, accession UA-2020-004. Previously transferred from the SMFA to the MFA archives.
  This series records include administrative, certification and accreditation, development, exhibition, facilities, financial, and education records including minutes; reports; correspondence; committee records; course catalogs; self-studies; clippings; photos, slides, and audiovisual materials recording exhibits and student and faculty work; building plans and architectural records; scrapbooks; and some art supplies. Materials date from 1875 to 2016.
  Administrative records from several SMFA deans date from the 1930s to 2013. The majority of materials are from Deborah Haigh Dluhy's tenure (1993 – 2010) and include reports, correspondence, meeting materials, budgets, proposals, self-study materials for the SMFA, and materials relating to the Board of Governors. Capital campaign records relate mostly to fundraising in the 1980s and 1990s. This includes reports, meeting minutes, directories of and notes concerning potential donors, and donor research material. It also includes materials relating to events, such as guest lists, invoices, program schedules, and invitations. Course programs and catalogs date from 1900 – 2015. Alongside this material are advertisements about exhibitions and publications from the school, including an independent paper, "the Underground" and a publication by Graham Harwood titled "if comix Mental."
  Records of the SMFA Self-Study for National Association of Schools of Art and Design consist of administrative documents such as internal reports, reports from other art schools, correspondence, mission statements, operating procedures, and newspaper clippings about the school dating from 2004 – 2010.
  Records of the SMFA's Massachusetts Department of Higher Education degree granting application and approval includes materials regarding the Program Application for New Degrees, which the SMFA submitted to the Massachusetts Department of Higher Education circa 2012. This application was part of the accreditation process the SMFA underwent in order to be able to offer the degrees of Bachelor of Fine Arts in Studio Art, Master of Fine Arts in Studio Art, and Honorary Doctorate of Fine Art.
  The bulk of the scrapbooks dating from 1878 to 1990 contain clippings, postcards, pamphlets, invitations, and photographs related to SMFA students and faculty and their artwork and exhibitions. Grand Tour scrapbooks dating from 1904 to 1913 and the Mary Hallowell Loud scrapbook dating from 1905 contain captioned postcards and photographs, tickets, itineraries, and narrative descriptions of artwork, museums, and travel across Europe. The personal scrapbook dating from 1910 to 1923 contains captioned photographs of family, friends, and classmates at the SMFA during this period.
  Art--Study and teaching; Administration and Governance -- Accreditation; Advancement; Facilities; Greater Boston arts; Museum of Fine Arts, Boston
  - SMFA development, 1980 -- 1990; UA133.001655 (Box 447)
  - SMFA development, 1980 -- 1990; UA133.001656 (Box 448)
  - SMFA development, 1980 -- 1990; UA133.001657 (Box 449)
  - SMFA development, 1980 -- 1990; UA133.001658 (Box 450)
  - SMFA development, 1980 -- 1990; UA133.001659 (Box 451)
  - SMFA construction records, 1986 -- 1991; UA133.001660 (Box 452)
  - SMFA construction records, 1986 -- 1991; UA133.001661 (Box 453)
  - SMFA construction records, 1986 -- 1991; UA133.001662 (Box 454)
  - SMFA retrofit and construction records, 1986 -- 1991; UA133.001663 (Box 455)
  - SMFA retrofit and construction records, 1986 -- 1991; UA133.001664 (Box 456)
  - SMFA retrofit and construction records, 1986 -- 1991; UA133.001665 (Box 457)
  - Publicity/correspondence, circa 1930s -- 1990; UA133.001666 (Box 458)
  - Publicity/correspondence, circa 1930s -- 1990; UA133.001667 (Box 459)
  - Publicity/correspondence, circa 1930s -- 1990; UA133.001668 (Box 460)
  - Publicity/correspondence, circa 1930s -- 1990; UA133.001669 (Box 461)
  - Publicity/correspondence, circa 1930s -- 1990; UA133.001670 (Box 462)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001672 (Box 464)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001673 (Box 465)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001674 (Box 466)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001675 (Box 467)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001676 (Box 468)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001677 (Box 469)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001678 (Box 470)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001679 (Box 471)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001680 (Box 472)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001681 (Box 473)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001683 (Box 475)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001684 (Box 476)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001685 (Box 477)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001686 (Box 478)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001687 (Box 479)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001688 (Box 480)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001689 (Box 481)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001690 (Box 482)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001691 (Box 483)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001692 (Box 484)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001693 (Box 485)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video oversize, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001694 (Box 486)
  - Clippings, photos, film, video oversize, 1960 -- 1997; UA133.001695 (Box 487)